domainnamewire.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy and Terms of Use - Domain Name Wire | Domain Name News & Website Stuff

By accessing DomainNameWire.com or DNW.com, you agree to the following terms of use and privacy policy.

**Privacy**

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://domainnamewire.com.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

This site may have contact forms in which you contact the site’s owner. If you use these forms, the information you submit (as well as your IP address) may be transmitted to us.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

When you visit the site, a system may present an email newsletter opt-in form to you. This form uses cookies to make sure that it shows the form periodically, rather than every time you visit.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Additionally, we use a third-party tool for email opt-in. If you submit your information to this tool, it will be transmitted to our email newsletter service.

### Analytics

This site also uses third-party tools for analytics and other purposes. For example, it uses Google Analytics to track the usage of the website. Certain information will be transmitted to Google in order to achieve this.

## Who we share your data with

Your data may be transmitted to third party services for the purposes of making the site operate, analytics, and plugins.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Your contact information

You can contact the site owner at andrew (at) domainnamewire.com

## Additional information

### How we protect your data

This website is hosted by GoDaddy. We use third-party security plugins to protect the security of this site. The site is built with WordPress.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

We have contracted with a third party to rectify any data breaches as quickly as possible.

**Terms of Use**

By using this site, you agree:

-That your IP address will be tracked when you leave a comment, a standard feature of WordPress  
-To not use profanity in comments  
-To not impersonate another individual or company  
-To not use a fictitious email when submitting a comment  
-To not advertise domain names for sale in comments  
-To not use automated programs to access Domain Name Wire without express written permission  
-That you will not re-publish Domain Name Wire articles in a way that violates our copyright. Violations of the copyright include publishing full text of Domain Name Wire articles on another site or in a commercial manner. This includes publishing more than snippets from the RSS feed.
